N Raghav

 \bigcirc N-Raghav | in N Raghav | \blacksquare raghavn
753@gmail.com | \blacksquare +91 9168067520

SUMMARY

I am currently pursuing a Bachelor of Technology Degree with a specialization in IoT. I am an avid robotics enthusiast and have done a few projects in it as well. I have built an RC Rescue Mission Robot, an automated plant watering system using Arduino, and a River Cleaner Robot. Currently, I am Stimuli for Technological Innovation and Research for Student, pursuing my undergraduate research titled "My Mind: A cognitive digital twin".

EDUCATION

2021 - Present	Bachelor's Degree at Shiv Nadar University Chennai	(CGPA: 8.5)
2021	JEE MAINS	(97.71 percentile)
2021	Class 12th CBSE Board	(94.2)
2019	Class 10th Some Board	(93.2)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Stimuli for Technological Innovation and Research Student

December 2022 - present

Special scholarship scheme through which Shiv Nadar University Chennai funds student projects from the first-year of study. Short-listed projects will be funded up to Rs. 30,000/- to carry out their ideas.

Robotics Club Representative

January 2022 - Present

Student Representative for "Potential" the Robotics Club of SNU Chennai.

Joint Secretary SNUC

January 2023 - March 2023

Student Representative for SNU Chennai in the joint cultural event "Instincts" organized by SSN and SNU Chennai

Head Organiser - Enchante

November 2022

Lead Organiser for the inaugural Freshers Day Event Enchante at SNU Chennai

YouTube Intern Head

May 2022 - July 2022

Responsible for content creation on YouTube for India's largest Non-Profit Organisation working on grassroots Football "India Khelo Football".

PROJECTS

My Mind: A Cognitive Digital Twin

Ongoing Project

The problem we are attempting to solve with the help of our research project is 'Student Mental Health'. Current branches of psychology have minimalist use in the advancement of Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Reinforcement learning to identify mental disorders. Our main objective as part of this research project is to utilize the untapped potential of AI, ML, and reinforcement learning along with the psychological test batteries to improvise the process of Identification of Mental Health Disorders. We aim to achieve this by trying to implement a concept called "Digital Twin" which can be defined as a virtual model designed to accurately reflect a physical object. We plan to create a cognitive digital twin of the brain of the patient and identify mental disorders.

Music Recommendation System

GitHub Link

Using Python libraries like Spotipy, Pandas, Numpy, and SKlearn, we created a music recommendation system. We utilized the principles of a Content-based recommendation system. My role in the project was the vectorization of the music properties and finding similar songs using cosine similarity.

Instagram User Analysis

GitHub Link

Utilization of MySQL and queries to perform data analysis. Applying concepts like ER diagrams, joins, and normalization to extract useful information for data analysis.

River Cleaner Robot

As the UN theme of marine water pollution was introduced, we participated in TRICKS. My role in this project was to identify techniques to build a floating robot and took part in the building of the robot. We won the 'BEST DESIGN' award and the 1st prize for the same.

SKILLS

Programming Skills C,C++,Python,Java

Technical Skills Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Agile Process, Digital Design ar

Technical Skills Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Agile Process, Digital Design and Microprocessors, Com-

puter Organisation and Architecture, Database Management System(MYSQL)

Extra Curricular Skills Part time You Tuber, Content Writing, Event Management, Football Player,

Social Media Management, Leadership, Orator